<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meandrous</title>
    <link>https://hean01.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Meandrous</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hean01.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>M02 - JAO mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/m02-jao-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/m02-jao-mead/</guid>
      <description>This post will be updated with a log of brew of one gallon JAO Mead. I have changed the recipe using D47 yeast as described in the linked post.
Day 0 - 2017-04-09 I followed the receipe from my earlier blog post. I measured the mead for an OG (Original Gravity) 1.093 and put the carboy on a kitchen bench for starting fermantation.
Day 1 - 2017-04-10 I check the fermentation process and saw now bubbles in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAO Mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/jao-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/jao-mead/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m interested in doing a melomel which is a mead with fruits. I found a recipe that I found interesting tasteful which is named JAO mead. I changed the yeast in the receipe to a white wine yeast Lavlin D47 which I have on the shelf.
This recipe is for one gallon mead.
 1.5 Kg honey 1 large orange 25 raisins 1 cinnamon stick 1 or two cloves 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M01 - My first mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/m01-my-first-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/m01-my-first-mead/</guid>
      <description>This post will be updated with a log of my journey brewing the show mead using the starter kit bought from PGW mentioned in earlier blog post.
Day 0 - 2017-04-02 I followed the receipe from the begin to end and was about spot on every step. I measured the mead for an OG (Original Gravity) 1.060 and put the carboy in a good place for fermentation.
Day 1 - 2017-04-03 Added the Fermaid-K nutrients as per receipe and stired a little and boom the foamy scum rasied out of the carboy and seemed to never stop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PGW Show mead starter kit</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/pgw-mead-startkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/pgw-mead-startkit/</guid>
      <description>I bought a mead start kit from PGW which included everything to start to create mead, all the equipments and the sanitizer, yeast and nutrient. This start kit is for creating 4 litres (1 gallon) show mead which is mead in its purest form, honey, water and yeast. The kit also includes a brewing instruction which I will describe below. This post will also be updated with a brew log as a reference for future brewing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midi sync Volca beats with Analog four</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/midi-sync-volca-beats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/midi-sync-volca-beats/</guid>
      <description>I just recently got my Volca Beats analog drum machine and wanted to sync it up with my Analog Four. To enable Volca Beats to sync with external device using midi you need to make sure that clock source is configured to auto.
While holding down func key and power on the volca device, you will enter configuration mode of the Volca Beats. Pressing play button will cancel any changes, record will save the changes and reboot your device.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>