<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Meandrous</title>
    <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Meandrous</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hean01.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gingerbeer</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/gingerbeer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/gingerbeer/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is for 10L of non alcoholic ginger beer using a ginger bug.
Recipe  10L water 1L table sugar 1dl grated ginger 6 lemons 3 limes   Grate the skin of 3 lemons and 3 limes
 Press the juice out of the lemons and limes and set aside
 Mix sugar, grated giner and grated skin into the water
 Bring the tea to a boil and turn of the heat and let the tea steep for an hour</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gingerbug</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/gingerbug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/gingerbug/</guid>
      <description>Gingerbug is a probiotic starter culture for making homemade soda, ginger beer etc. A gingerbug is very simple to create and it will take approximate 4-6 days to get one ready for use. Then it is added to a soda tea and bottled to build up a nice fizzy soda. This receipe is will give you about 1L of gingerbug and it is good for a 10 to 15L final product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C02 - Bravo apple juice cider high ABV</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/c02-bravo-cider-habv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/c02-bravo-cider-habv/</guid>
      <description>I have bought a co2 regulator with trapetz adapter for connection to a 430g &amp;ldquo;soda stream&amp;rdquo; c02 bottle and a PET adapter to push co2 into PET bottles. This allows me to kill the yeast, clear the brew and do back sweetening before bottling.
This brew will be based on blog post but with following modification; Add more sugar for higer ABV to compensate for the back sweetening using Bravo juice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous brew of Kombucha</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/kombucha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/kombucha/</guid>
      <description>Kombucha is a non alcoholic fermented beverage which is produced using a symbiotic culture of bacteria and yeast (SCOBY) and sweetened black tea. You can do batches of Kombucha or setup a continuous brewing, this blog will describe the process of continuous brewing.
First you need to get hold on a SCOBY, you can either buy one online or grow one by your self. To grow one your self you need to get hold on a unpasteurized Kombucha drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bravo Apple juice Cider</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/bravo-apple-juice-cider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/bravo-apple-juice-cider/</guid>
      <description>I got interested to brew a hard cider to this midsummer. I found that someone had success to brew a cider on a specific store bought apple cider (Bravo äppel juice) available here in Sweden. So this is my go at that.
The docket on the juice package told me that there are 9.5g sugar per 100ml. This means 95g per liter and that would give me a cider with approximated ABV of 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C01 - Bravo apple juice cider</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/c01-bravo-juice-cider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/c01-bravo-juice-cider/</guid>
      <description>This post will be updated with a log of my journey brewing the a Bravo apple juice hard cider using the recipe mentioned in post blog post.
     #chart_container { position: relative; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; } #chart { position: relative; left: 40px; } .rickshaw_graph .x_tick .title { bottom: -24px; left: -18px; } #y_axis { position: absolute; top: 0; bottom: 0; width: 40px; }       $.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine cooler</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/wine-cooler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/wine-cooler/</guid>
      <description>I found that one could make a sugar wash (sugar wine) as a base for wine cooler. This is raw sugar, water, nutrients and yeast.
I calculated that i needed 250g sugar per liter water to reach a ABV 14.7% which seems to be a good target for a wine cooler base. My idea is to ferment all sugars and kill the yeast in the sugar wash, then use a essences for soda streamer and the soda streamer to carbonate a alcoholic beverage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mead numbers and math examples</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/mead-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/mead-numbers/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will talk about how to calculate sugar volumes for targeting a specific sweetness and or alcohol of a mead. In a recipe the final gravity is your target and you will choose a yeast to control the ABV and on top of that the amount of honey. Here follows a table of ranges of final gravity for a mead for different sweetness.
   Sweetness Oechele Gravity     Dry 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M05 - Pineapple and Coconut mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/m05-pineapple-coconut-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/m05-pineapple-coconut-mead/</guid>
      <description>This is the brewlog for Pineapple and Coconut mead recipe I put together.
Here follows the fermentation graph over time for this mead.
     #chart_container { position: relative; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; } #chart { position: relative; left: 40px; } .rickshaw_graph .x_tick .title { bottom: -24px; left: -18px; } #y_axis { position: absolute; top: 0; bottom: 0; width: 40px; }       $.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pineapple and Coconut mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/pineapple-coconut-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/pineapple-coconut-mead/</guid>
      <description>Heres my recipe for a Pineapple and Coconut mead. I will base this on PGW show mead recipe but increasing the amount of honey to 3 x 650g for a sweet mead.
 5dl + 3dl coconut flakes 1 pineapple, about 1 litre of pineapple cubes 1.95 Kg wild flower honey 2.5g Lavlin D47 yeast 6g Fermaid-K nutrients  Receipe  Santize all of your equipment
 Chop up the pineapple into 1 cm cubes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry and Raspberry mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/blueberry-raspberry-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/blueberry-raspberry-mead/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to create a medium sweet melomel with blueberry and raspberry. I started out with PGW show mead receipe and changed it to the following.
 250g frozen blueberries 250g frozen raspberries 1.5kg honey 2.5g Lavlin D47  Receipe  Santize all of your equipment
 Put the frozen fruits into a bowl in a hot warm water bath
 Heat up water 2 litre of water to 30° celcius and stir up the honey into a must, then pour the fruits and juice into the cattle and stir for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M04 - Blueberry and Raspberry mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/m04-blueberry-raspberry-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/m04-blueberry-raspberry-mead/</guid>
      <description>This is the brewlog for Blueberry and Raspberry mead recipe I put together. Here follows the fermentation graphs.
I followed the recipe as advertised and was finished around 21:30. The must looks very dark as you can see in the picture below. Raspberry seeds seems to gather up on the bottom but the rest of fruit is floating at the top of the carboy.
Here follows the fermentation graph over time for this mead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Degassing using vacuum</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/degassing-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/degassing-mead/</guid>
      <description>I read up on degassing process before bottling the mead and found the approach of using vacuum do draw out the gas from the mead. After some more digging into the subject I found that a manual vacuum pump, used for resealing opened wine bottles could be used for the purpose. This seemed to be a very simple approach to degassing. No need to dipping a tool that need to sanitzed to swirl the mead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M03 - Medium mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/m03-medium-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/m03-medium-mead/</guid>
      <description>This time I wanted to set a sweeter batch of mead. I followed the PGW mead receipt but bumped up the honey from 1.25Kg to 1.5Kg. I will updated this post with more information during the timeline of fermentation and aging.
     #chart_container { position: relative; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; } #chart { position: relative; left: 40px; } .rickshaw_graph .x_tick .title { bottom: -24px; left: -18px; } #y_axis { position: absolute; top: 0; bottom: 0; width: 40px; }       $.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M02 - JAO mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/m02-jao-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/m02-jao-mead/</guid>
      <description>This post will be updated with a log of brew of one gallon JAO Mead. I have changed the recipe using D47 yeast as described in the linked post.
     #chart_container { position: relative; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; } #chart { position: relative; left: 40px; } .rickshaw_graph .x_tick .title { bottom: -24px; left: -18px; } #y_axis { position: absolute; top: 0; bottom: 0; width: 40px; }       $.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAO Mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/jao-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/jao-mead/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m interested in doing a melomel which is a mead with fruits. I found a recipe that I found interesting tasteful which is named JAO mead. I changed the yeast in the receipe to a white wine yeast Lavlin D47 which I have on the shelf.
This recipe is for one gallon mead.
 1.5 Kg honey 1 large orange 25 raisins 1 cinnamon stick 1 or two cloves 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M01 - My first mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/m01-my-first-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/m01-my-first-mead/</guid>
      <description>This post will be updated with a log of my journey brewing the show mead using the starter kit bought from PGW mentioned in earlier blog post.
     #chart_container { position: relative; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; } #chart { position: relative; left: 40px; } .rickshaw_graph .x_tick .title { bottom: -24px; left: -18px; } #y_axis { position: absolute; top: 0; bottom: 0; width: 40px; }       $.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PGW Show mead starter kit</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/pgw-mead-startkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/pgw-mead-startkit/</guid>
      <description>I bought a mead start kit from PGW which included everything to start to create mead, all the equipments and the sanitizer, yeast and nutrient. This start kit is for creating 4 litres (1 gallon) show mead which is mead in its purest form, honey, water and yeast. The kit also includes a brewing instruction which I will describe below. This post will also be updated with a brew log as a reference for future brewing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midi sync Volca beats with Analog four</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/midi-sync-volca-beats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/midi-sync-volca-beats/</guid>
      <description>I just recently got my Volca Beats analog drum machine and wanted to sync it up with my Analog Four. To enable Volca Beats to sync with external device using midi you need to make sure that clock source is configured to auto.
While holding down func key and power on the volca device, you will enter configuration mode of the Volca Beats. Pressing play button will cancel any changes, record will save the changes and reboot your device.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>