<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipe on Meandrous</title>
    <link>https://hean01.github.io/tags/recipe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipe on Meandrous</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hean01.github.io/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bravo Apple juice Cider</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/bravo-apple-juice-cider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/bravo-apple-juice-cider/</guid>
      <description>I got interested to bew a hard cider to this midsummer. I found that someone had success to brew a cider on a specific store bought apple cider (Bravo äppel juice) available here in sweden. So this is my go at that.
The docket on the juice package told me that there are 9.5g sugar per 100ml. This means 95g per liter and that would give me a cider with approximated ABV of 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pineapple and Coconut mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/pineapple-coconut-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/pineapple-coconut-mead/</guid>
      <description>Heres my recipe for a Pineapple and Coconut mead. I will base this on PGW show mead recipe but increasing the amount of honey to 3 x 650g for a sweet mead.
 5dl + 3dl coconut flakes 1 pineapple, about 1 litre of pineapple cubes 1.95 Kg wild flower honey 2.5g Lavlin D47 yeast 6g Fermaid-K nutrients  Receipe  Santize all of your equipment
 Chop up the pineapple into 1 cm cubes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry and Raspberry mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/blueberry-raspberry-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/blueberry-raspberry-mead/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to create a medium sweet melomel with blueberry and raspberry. I started out with PGW show mead receipe and changed it to the following.
 250g frozen blueberries 250g frozen raspberries 1.5kg honey 2.5g Lavlin D47  Receipe  Santize all of your equipment
 Put the frozen fruits into a bowl in a hot warm water bath
 Heat up water 2 litre of water to 30° celcius and stir up the honey into a must, then pour the fruits and juice into the cattle and stir for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAO Mead</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/jao-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/jao-mead/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m interested in doing a melomel which is a mead with fruits. I found a recipe that I found interesting tasteful which is named JAO mead. I changed the yeast in the receipe to a white wine yeast Lavlin D47 which I have on the shelf.
This recipe is for one gallon mead.
 1.5 Kg honey 1 large orange 25 raisins 1 cinnamon stick 1 or two cloves 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PGW Show mead starter kit</title>
      <link>https://hean01.github.io/post/pgw-mead-startkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>henrik.4e@gmail.com (Henrik Andersson)</author>
      <guid>https://hean01.github.io/post/pgw-mead-startkit/</guid>
      <description>I bought a mead start kit from PGW which included everything to start to create mead, all the equipments and the sanitizer, yeast and nutrient. This start kit is for creating 4 litres (1 gallon) show mead which is mead in its purest form, honey, water and yeast. The kit also includes a brewing instruction which I will describe below. This post will also be updated with a brew log as a reference for future brewing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>